<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-25T01:43:01+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aleksandra Samonek</title><author><name>Aleksandra Samonek</name></author><entry><title type="html">7 ways to use the lockdown to become a better academic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/academia/2020/03/24/lockdown-academics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 ways to use the lockdown to become a better academic" /><published>2020-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/academia/2020/03/24/lockdown-academics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/academia/2020/03/24/lockdown-academics.html">&lt;p&gt;The recent lockdown measures introduced in response to the new coronavirus pandemic, which force researchers and educators to forego in-person team work and teaching, are likely to continue for at last another few weeks. As researchers we are rather lucky, considering the current circumstances, as more often than not we are able to continue with our projects and receive salaries throughout the lockdown period. This being said, the feelings of isolation and loss of control seem to spread among academics just as quickly as among other people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;60%&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-03-25-hopeful.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Over the past few weeks I have seen some academics take back control over their working hours and propose ways to beat the pandemic overwhelm with initiative and opitimism. I tried out many of these strategies, so I decided to share a few of my personal favorites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-1-freshen-up-your-writing-regimen&quot;&gt;№ 1. Freshen up your writing regimen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially for junior researchers like myself, writing and research are a centerpiece of everyday work. Why not use the extra time off some of the pressure related to our main tasks and make them more engaging? Here are some strategies to try out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Organize a round of academic NaNoWriMo&lt;/b&gt; in April with friends and co-workers. Nicole Roccas (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@nicole.marie.roccas/10-alternatives-to-nanowrimo-for-nonfiction-and-academic-writers-f4f5c6932283&quot;&gt;in her 2017 post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;) listed some ideas for academic NaNoWriMo projects to start with, including the following goals:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Write a full draft of a paper of a book chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Finish a previous writing project that has fallen through the cracks.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rework a failed or rejected draft which still shows potential.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Write a book proposal.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set daily time or character quota per day for 30 days.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keep a research journal for 30 days. (As a logician, I found this one to be particularly amusing and refreshing.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Take an online course to level-up your writing and written communication skills.&lt;/b&gt; For example, these courses have some useful content on post-graduate writing:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://courses.edx.org/courses/course-v1:WitsX+WCMx+3T2019/course/&quot;&gt;Academic writing for clarity and meaning from WitsX&lt;/a&gt;: includes helpful concepts such as the golden thread, the fog index, rules of editing for clarity, &lt;i&gt;etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/sciwrite&quot;&gt;Writing in the Sciences from Stanford&lt;/a&gt;: a course in scientific writing which includes many exercises for quality writing and dealing with writing anxiety.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Follow a project course or set up a writing group to give each other feedback&lt;/b&gt; on that text you have been meaning to come back for the past two years. For the former, try &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/how-to-write-a-scientific-paper&quot;&gt;How to Write and Publish a Scientific Paper (Project course) from l’École polytechnique&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-2-explore-journals-in-depth-and-find-pleasure-in-reading-papers-outside-your-immediate-research-goals&quot;&gt;№ 2. Explore journals in depth and find pleasure in reading papers outside your immediate research goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journals in my field, and likely also in yours, regularly publish high quality papers authored by top researchers. These papers not only describe valuable results, but often make for a pleasant read. I sometimes hear people say: &lt;i&gt;Oh, if only I had the time to sit down and enjoy this journal that I like, like it’s grad school all over again.&lt;/i&gt; Well, now is the time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, these logic hotspots all have been updated several times since the beginning of this month and are likely to provide you with new food for thought on the daily:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/logcom/advance-articles&quot;&gt;Journal of Logic and Computation (Advance articles)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/review-of-symbolic-logic/firstview&quot;&gt;The Review of Symbolic Logic (FirstView)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/list/math.LO/recent&quot;&gt;arXiv.org Logic (with daily updates)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://philsci-archive.pitt.edu/cgi/latest_days2?n=30&quot;&gt;philsci (latest additions)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-3-push-your-research-project-even-further&quot;&gt;№ 3. Push your research project even further&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing you can do is take back your holiday time &lt;i&gt;before&lt;/i&gt; it’s the holidays again. Many of us work intensely through summer, but a lot of this work can be completed now with the extra time that we save from daily commute to the university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With many 2020 academic events cancelled, you stand a pretty good chance of organizing some quality time for yourself or your friends and family in summer (see also № 7.), so whatever you have been planning to do in July and August when &lt;i&gt;you have more time&lt;/i&gt;, do it now.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;60%&quot; src=&quot;/images/2020-03-25-doitnow.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-4-become-a-better-teacher-or-science-communicator&quot;&gt;№ 4. Become a better teacher or science communicator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several things which you may do now to become a better teacher or science communicator. Some of them include creative work, like planning imaginary syllabi of your course and MOOCs, while others will allow you to sit back and listen to a bunch of education professionals telling you what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Come up with an idea for a MOOC in your AoS&lt;/b&gt;. Check out the major online education platforms to see whether there is demand for your class and then plan the content like you would for any other course. Try pitching the idea to your colleagues and students and draw them into the project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Use online classes to learn how to become a more equitable teacher and a more socially engaged scientist.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://courses.edx.org/courses/course-v1:MITx+0.503x+1T2020&quot;&gt;Becoming a More Equitable Educator: Mindsets and Practices from MITx (enrollment open)&lt;/a&gt;: a course on how to encourage students from different backgrounds, focus on their strengths and build a more equitable teaching mindset.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/tools-for-academic-engagement-in-public-policy&quot;&gt;Tools for Academic Engagement in Public Policy from MITx (enrollment open)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/leaders-of-learning&quot;&gt;Leaders of Learning from HarvardX (enrollment open)&lt;/a&gt;: a course on how to develop your own theory of learning and about how science will change the future of learning.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/open-science-sharing-your-research-with-the-world&quot;&gt;Open Science: Sharing Your Research with the World from DelftX (starts in May)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-5-dive-into-a-new-topic-or-field-logic-anyone&quot;&gt;№ 5. Dive into a new topic or field (logic, anyone?)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reach out to people from outside your AoS or take time to read an introduction to a field that is new to you. Whatever it is, as long as it makes you curious, you will learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ekhm, if you feel like checking what logic has to offer in terms of potentially interesting problems, feel free to contact me &lt;i&gt;via&lt;/i&gt; email or any of my social networks. I can set you up with a reading list or learning tools in no time and will try to answer any questions that come up as you explore the new topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-6-gain-a-new-skill-or-contribute-to-a-skill-based-project&quot;&gt;№ 6. Gain a new skill or contribute to a skill-based project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options are endless, but I would recommend planning something with clear goals to give your mind some rest from the chaos of day-to-day events. What skill would let you get ahead? Perhaps you can get to level 3 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wanikani.com/#&quot;&gt;WaniKani&lt;/a&gt; in a month? Maybe you can learn the basics of a new programming language or a new framework? Or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ossblog.org/learn-tex-programming-free-books/&quot;&gt;learn new things about TeX&lt;/a&gt; which you can use in your research?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not feel like starting a new hobby, consider improving on the skills you already have by, &lt;i&gt;e. g.&lt;/i&gt;, contributing to a worthy project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out this guide on &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.guide/how-to-contribute/&quot;&gt;how to contribute to open source&lt;/a&gt;, or&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this guide on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.firsttimersonly.com/&quot;&gt;what to if do you have never contributed to an open source project before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-7-improve-your-mental-health-and-overall-happiness&quot;&gt;№ 7. Improve your mental health and overall happiness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tip comes last although it’s probably the most important of all. Your mental state is even more of a priority now, so perhaps it’s worh making it into a project of sorts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is one way to do it systematically, with an option to contribute to a legitimate research project in psychology. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bespacific.com/yales-most-popular-class-ever-is-available-free-online/&quot;&gt;Sabrina I. Pacifici&lt;/a&gt; called this online course &lt;i&gt;the most popular class in Yale’s history&lt;/i&gt; and after starting with it I understand its popularity. &lt;i&gt;The Science of Well-Being&lt;/i&gt; by Laurie Santos is available to audit for free and includes all the resources which you will need to easily track and improve on your happiness levels in the coming weeks, like the ReWi app, which you can get from &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/rewi/id914948787&quot;&gt;AppStore&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=edu.yale.rewi&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/the-science-of-well-being/home/welcome&quot;&gt;Go to the course: The Science of Well-Being&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-you-have-any-more-tips-on-how-to-rock-even-harder-in-these-times-of-doom-please-let-me-know&quot;&gt;If you have any more tips on how to rock even harder in these times of doom, please let me know!&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name>Aleksandra Samonek</name></author><summary type="html">The recent lockdown measures introduced in response to the new coronavirus pandemic, which force researchers and educators to forego in-person team work and teaching, are likely to continue for at last another few weeks. As researchers we are rather lucky, considering the current circumstances, as more often than not we are able to continue with our projects and receive salaries throughout the lockdown period. This being said, the feelings of isolation and loss of control seem to spread among academics just as quickly as among other people.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction to Complex Predicate Calculus for Databases</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/events/2019/12/13/introduction-cpc-talk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Complex Predicate Calculus for Databases" /><published>2019-12-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/12/13/introduction-cpc-talk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/events/2019/12/13/introduction-cpc-talk.html">&lt;p&gt;On December 19, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Olga_Poller&quot;&gt;Olga Poller&lt;/a&gt; and me will give a talk about our joint research at the Departamental Seminar of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://filozofia.uj.edu.pl/en_GB/department-of-logical-rethorics&quot;&gt;Section of Logical Rhetoric&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;venue-and-time&quot;&gt;Venue and time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17:30 - 19:00 &lt;br /&gt;
Room 28, I floor, Collegium Broscianum &lt;br /&gt;
Institute of Philosophy, Jagiellonian University&lt;br /&gt;
ul. Grodzka 52, Kraków, Poland&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-to-complex-predicate-calculus-for-databases&quot;&gt;Introduction to Complex Predicate Calculus for databases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CPC (Complex Predicate Calculus) represents the process of creating complex predicates in the natural language in a such a way that the result of this process (which we will call a &lt;em&gt;query&lt;/em&gt;) constitutes information included in a database. Initially, CPC was designed to represent prepositions, but it soon turned out that the rules of CPC can be applied much more universally, to a much wider class of phrases. The goal of this talk is to introduce the philosophical motivation behind CPC and also its theoretical foundations, such as the language, syntax and the CPC model. We will also discuss some preliminary results concerning compositionality and the rules of CPC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pl-wprowadzenie-do-rachunku-złożonych-predykatów-dla-baz-danych&quot;&gt;(PL) Wprowadzenie do rachunku złożonych predykatów dla baz danych&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachunek złożonych predykatów CPC (Complex Predicate Calculus) pozwala na reprezentację procesu tworzenia złożonych predykatów w języku naturalnym w taki sposób, że wynik tego procesu można zapisać w postaci bazy danych. W pierwotnym założeniu CPC miał służyć do reprezentacji wyrażeń przyimkowych, jednak wkrótce okazało się, że reguły CPC pozwalają na reprezentację o wiele szerszej klasy wyrażeń. Celem tego wystąpienia będzie przestawienie motywacji filozoficznej oraz podstaw teoretycznych CPC, w szczególności podstawowych definicji, takich jak język, zasady syntaktyczne oraz model CPC. Przedstawimy także wstępne wyniki dotyczące kompozycjonalności oraz reguł CPC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aleksandra Samonek</name></author><summary type="html">On December 19, 2019, Olga Poller and me will give a talk about our joint research at the Departamental Seminar of the Section of Logical Rhetoric.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Group in ‘Probabilistic logics and probabilistic networks’ at UCLouvain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/events/2019/10/29/progic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Group in 'Probabilistic logics and probabilistic networks' at UCLouvain" /><published>2019-10-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/10/29/progic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/events/2019/10/29/progic.html">&lt;p&gt;At UCLouvain we are opening a reading group focused on the following book:  Haenni, R., Romeijn, J. W., Wheeler, G., &amp;amp; Williamson, J. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Probabilistic logics and probabilistic networks&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 350). Springer Science &amp;amp; Business Media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book concerns the results of a research project conducted by Haenni, Romeijn, Wheeler and Williamson between 2006 and 2008. (View the project page &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.kent.ac.uk/jonw/projects/progicnet-probabilistic-logic-and-probabilistic-networks/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the semester I will update this page to include the date and time of our meetings, as well as handouts and links. All interested persons are invited to join in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Meeting 1: Chapters 1 and 2&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Date and time (preliminary): TBA&lt;br /&gt;
Venue: Collège Mercier, Place du Cardinal Mercier, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/handouts/progicnet/ASamonekProgicAndNetworksReadingGroup-Handout01Chapters01-ver1.0.pdf&quot;&gt; [Download Handout no 1.] &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aleksandra Samonek</name></author><summary type="html">At UCLouvain we are opening a reading group focused on the following book: Haenni, R., Romeijn, J. W., Wheeler, G., &amp;amp; Williamson, J. (2010). Probabilistic logics and probabilistic networks (Vol. 350). Springer Science &amp;amp; Business Media.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Can intended models of mathematical theories change over time? Work In Progress talk at UCLouvain on October 16, 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/events/2019/10/11/wip-seminar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can intended models of mathematical theories change over time? Work In Progress talk at UCLouvain on October 16, 2019" /><published>2019-10-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-10-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/10/11/wip-seminar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/events/2019/10/11/wip-seminar.html">&lt;p&gt;On October 16, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cris.vub.be/en/persons/colin-jakob-rittberg(b0bc2ff1-4b71-47a2-941b-bd97d9cf4144).html&quot;&gt;Colin Rittberg&lt;/a&gt; and myself will give a joint talk about our upcoming paper on intended models in mathematical practice at the Work In Progress seminar of the CEFISES at UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve. The seminar is open and all interested are invited to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;venue-and-time&quot;&gt;Venue and time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:00 - 17:00 &lt;br /&gt;
Salle Ladrière (a.124 - 1st floor), Collège Mercier &lt;br /&gt;
Place du Cardinal Mercier, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-intended-models-of-mathematical-theories-change-over-time&quot;&gt;Can intended models of mathematical theories change over time?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work of philosophers of mathematical practice has challenged our understanding of various concepts in mathematics. For example, observing how mathematical proofs develop over time and how they relate to our understanding of mathematical objects and phenomena, led Hanna (1989, 2002); Mancosu (2008); Macbeth (2012); Van Bendegem (2014) and others, to a conclusion that the adequate description of the notion of mathematical proof relies on processes that are much more complex than syntactic constructs and manipulations. In our paper we challenge another concept which has been highly idealised in classical philosophy of mathematics, namely the concept of an intended model. We will contest the widely accepted understanding of an intended model as simply one guaranteed to be found among all the models of a theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will discuss the notion of the intended model in the context of the distinction between what we call &lt;em&gt;content-driven practices&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;content-creating practices&lt;/em&gt;, borrowing from Lakatos’ notion of the informal (&lt;em&gt;inhaltliche&lt;/em&gt;) mathematics (&lt;em&gt;cf.&lt;/em&gt; Krause and Arenhart (2016, p. 63)). Content-driven mathematical practices aim to explicate in terms of a mathematical theory some content or structure, or the so-called &lt;em&gt;intended model&lt;/em&gt;, which is assumed to be given in advance: content first, theory later. We intentionally use the term &lt;em&gt;mathematical theory&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;axiomatic theory&lt;/em&gt;, as we aim highlight the order in which mathematical concepts emerge. For example, number theory had featured an intended model of natural numbers long before the development of PA. Another case is geometry trying to capture the realities of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In content-creating mathematical practices no such content is given in advance. Instead, an axiomatic theory defines a class of structures, its own object of study. The order is reversed compared to content-creating practices, that is we obtain theory first and content later. Classic examples of content-creating practices include algebra and graph theory, where the axiomatic theory is not meant to explicate any intended structure, but rather serves as a starting point of the process of discovering a class of structures which are presumed to be of mathematical interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming that some mathematical practices are content-driven, where does their content come from? A plausible answer to this question has been proposed by Ferreirós, namely the content of mathematical theories arises from the historical development of “technical practices” (Ferreirós, 2016, p.40). We will supplement Ferreirós’ case with an example from contemporary set theory, where in the current axiom selection debate, the theory has caught up to the content in ways that require (and have produced) new ways of understanding the intended model of set theory. Our principal case study to show this is H. Woodin’s Ultimate L argument (Woodin, 2017). We will also touch upon other proposals by Steel and Magidor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will further argue that the understanding of an intended model for a given discipline of mathematics has the potential to change over time and even erode, so that the practice no longer aims at explicating an intended model at all. In this, within the same mathematical theory we can observe a shift from content-driven to content-creating practice. Starting with von Neumann, we will introduce the notion of epistemic pluralism and touch upon Väänänen’s work to formalise the notion. Epistemic pluralism already erodes, but does not discard, the idea of an intended model for a content-driven practice. We then report on how Hamkins shifts pluralism from the epistemic to metaphysical. We argue that with this shift, Hamkins places theory before content in the sense of our paper, and thereby suggests to transform set theory from a content-driven to a content-creating practice.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aleksandra Samonek</name></author><summary type="html">On October 16, 2019, Colin Rittberg and myself will give a joint talk about our upcoming paper on intended models in mathematical practice at the Work In Progress seminar of the CEFISES at UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve. The seminar is open and all interested are invited to join.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fighting Fake News: our winning project at Hack Belgium 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/programming/2019/03/30/hack-belgium-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fighting Fake News: our winning project at Hack Belgium 2019" /><published>2019-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/programming/2019/03/30/hack-belgium-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/programming/2019/03/30/hack-belgium-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend (March 28 - 30, 2019) our team took first place at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackbelgium.be&quot;&gt;Hack Belgium 2019&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Credible, Engaging Media&lt;/em&gt; category (&lt;em&gt;Creating new experiences and new sources of trust&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
We were especially interested in the problem of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackbelgium.be/experiencing-true-media/&quot;&gt;creating smarter media consumers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our app, called &lt;em&gt;Jamnik&lt;/em&gt;, adds a “credibility layer” to links shared in feeds and private conversations on Facebook, Twitter, WhatsApp, &lt;em&gt;etc.&lt;/em&gt;, by visualising the level of reliability of the news source in the link preview and under a thumbnail of a published link. The analysis of credibility focuses on targeting automatically generated content, forged images and videos, and sources related to known fake news generators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our priorities were neutrality, transparency of the evaluation process and user-friendliness, including intuitive representation of the evaluation, fast delivery and eliminating the need of case-by-case evaluation assistance from the user. You can read the upshot of our idea in &lt;a href=&quot;https://prezi.com/p/ybpjfpb7guto/hack-belgium-2019/&quot;&gt;the presentation delivered during Hack Belgium 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/asamonek/asamonek.github.io/master/images/2019-03-30-hbteam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our team&quot; title=&quot;Our team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank the members of my team, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/danny-moeuthwil-057417100/&quot;&gt;Danny Moeuthwil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ben-bornemann-b5898377/&quot;&gt;Ben Bornemann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/gaetan-henry-8ba778132/&quot;&gt;Gaetan Henry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-michaux/&quot;&gt;Stéphanie Michaux&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/abali-essende-59355129/&quot;&gt;Abali Essende&lt;/a&gt;, for the three days of fruitful work and excellent company.&lt;br /&gt;
I also thank our mentors and workshop facilitators, particularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/florisdaelemans&quot;&gt;Floris Daelemans&lt;/a&gt; of VRT for his invaluable feedback during critical moments of the project development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for news about project &lt;em&gt;Jamnik&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aleksandra Samonek</name></author><summary type="html">Last weekend (March 28 - 30, 2019) our team took first place at Hack Belgium 2019 in the Credible, Engaging Media category (Creating new experiences and new sources of trust). We were especially interested in the problem of creating smarter media consumers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">[Extended deadline] CfP ExLog 2019: Explaining explanation using new developments in logic and formal semantics (UCLouvain, 6-8 May 2019)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/13/cfp-exlog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Extended deadline] CfP ExLog 2019: Explaining explanation using new developments in logic and formal semantics (UCLouvain, 6-8 May 2019)" /><published>2019-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/13/cfp-exlog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/13/cfp-exlog.html">&lt;p&gt;On 6-8 May 2019 we are organising a conference at UCLouvain in Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium. The full topic of the conference is the following: &lt;em&gt;Explaining explanation using new developments in logic and formal semantics. Hyperintensionality, relevance, counterfactuals, grounding and truth-maker semantics&lt;/em&gt;. You can find more information about the scope on &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/view/exlog2019&quot;&gt;the conference website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of invited speakers includes Hannes Leitgeb, Francesca Poggiolesi, Friederike Moltmann, Raymundo Morado, Joke Meheus, Kit Fine and J. Michael Dunn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://easychair.org/conferences/?conf=exlog2019&quot;&gt;Go directly to the submission page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently the deadline for submissions is &lt;strong&gt;23 March 2019&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aleksandra Samonek</name></author><summary type="html">On 6-8 May 2019 we are organising a conference at UCLouvain in Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium. The full topic of the conference is the following: Explaining explanation using new developments in logic and formal semantics. Hyperintensionality, relevance, counterfactuals, grounding and truth-maker semantics. You can find more information about the scope on the conference website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hypothetical Reasoning. From Formal Learning Theory to Machine Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/conditionals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hypothetical Reasoning. From Formal Learning Theory to Machine Learning" /><published>2017-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/conditionals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/01/conditionals.html">&lt;p&gt;The preliminary title of my doctoral dissertation is &lt;em&gt;Hypothetical Reasoning. From Formal Learning Theory to Machine Learning&lt;/em&gt;. My research is embedded in a broader project conducted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Peter_Verdee&quot;&gt;Peter Verdée&lt;/a&gt; entitled &lt;em&gt;Relevance criteria in entailment, epistemic grounding and counterfactuals: semantic and linguistic aspects&lt;/em&gt;. The project is funded by Fonds Spécial de Recherche (FSR) and started on March 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of my doctoral thesis is to obtain an interpretation of certain conditional sentences of the natural language in terms of &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/referenceworkentry/10.1007%2F978-1-4419-1428-6_444&quot;&gt;formal learning theory&lt;/a&gt;; and more specifically, conditional sentences which correspond to various forms of hypothetical reasoning. This problem relates to an analogous program of interpreting conditional sentences in machine learning, in particular to the issue of opinion mining and feature- or topic-based sentiment analysis (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D09-1019&quot;&gt;Narayanan, Liu and Choudhary (2009)&lt;/a&gt; for an example of how to use conditional analysis to assign positive, neutral or negative sentiments to topics or product features).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An additional objective of my work is to ensure that the obtained interpretation satisfies certain relevance and explainability criteria, which in machine learning correspond to the problem of black box interpretability. The following two aspects of my dissertation are particularly relevant:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the interpretation of the process of hypothetical reasoning which I propose can be applied uniformly to human and machine learners, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the probabilistic framework I use allows for producing explanations of all related processes, contributing to increased interpretability of certain machine learning models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Aleksandra Samonek</name></author><summary type="html">The preliminary title of my doctoral dissertation is Hypothetical Reasoning. From Formal Learning Theory to Machine Learning. My research is embedded in a broader project conducted by Peter Verdée entitled Relevance criteria in entailment, epistemic grounding and counterfactuals: semantic and linguistic aspects. The project is funded by Fonds Spécial de Recherche (FSR) and started on March 1, 2017.</summary></entry></feed>